### **BENJAMIN FOLKS**

E: bfolks2@gmail.com • M: (630)-217-5872 1143 W Wrightwood Ave #1F, Chicago, IL 60614 https://github.com/bfolks2

#### APPLICATIONS-SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Multi-faceted engineer with experience working on project teams to develop software solutions in numerous fast-paced environments, including Stryker Medical, NASA at Glenn Research Center, and Woodward at Rock Cut Campus. Combines practical and technical knowledge to develop efficient software UX solutions using Object Oriented Programming in VBA/VB.NET developers.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

PythonHTML/CSSJavascript/jQueryBootstrapMatlab

- Online Python and Django Full Stack Developer Bootcamp
- Created multi-application projects with Django/Python using Atom IDE, designed to interact with user input and Document Object Model events

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Microsoft Visual Studio
 VB.NET
 VB.NET
 ESPRIT CAD-CAM
 SolidWorks 3D CAD

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# DP Technology - ESPRIT • Rosemont, IL • July 2012 - Present

Developer and supplier of computer-aided manufacturing (CAM) software for a full range of machine tool applications, including milling, turning, wire EDM, and multi-tasking machine tools.

### Senior Applications-Software Engineer

- Manage customer-specific enhancement proposals from concept to finished program using
   Object Oriented Programming within the software API
- Utilize customer feedback obtained during trainings and consultations to plan and create additional VB.NET/VBA applications within the software API for improving software UX
- Train customers in utilizing VBA expression builders to increase programming automation
- Travel onsite to both private and US government clients to oversee technical projects

# Noteworthy Achievements

- Created and managed multiple Object-Oriented Programming projects from start to finish
  - Produced numerous VBA modules designed to increase automation of the software's default technology settings and enhance UX
  - Designed direct-to-customer Add-Ins for ~\$50,000 total in license/onsite cost
- Supervised 35+ onsite customer consultations amounting to over 130 days
- Managed 20 week-long part processing classes, totaling over 200 trainees
- Consulted remotely with engineers at **Woodward Inc.** (Dec 2

(Dec 2016 – Feb 2017)

- Created Add-In within VB.NET to improve efficiency when generating coordinate rotation manufacturing programs for GE Aviation Systems reverse thrust components
- Sub-contracted engineer at Northstar Aerospace Inc.

(Feb 2016-Apr 2016)

 Built text editing solution using the StreamReader and StreamWriter classes for converting current G-Code output into the desired format

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Aerospace Engineering
UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS • Urbana-Champaign, IL • 2011
FAA Certified Private Pilot - Instrument Rating
Certified SolidWorks Mechanical Design Professional